情况如何 ?
How we doing?
我想我们能擦边过去
Okay Ltd. I think I've got it lined up pretty close.
不能靠得太近
No such thing as close.
- 要不就穿过去, 要不就是死
- 好吧
You thread the needle, or we're dead.
- Right.
就这么办吧, 照你说的做
It's ok, you can do it
慢点, 别紧张
Nice and easy
Ok, 我想现在已经可以叫他们开门了
Ok, I think we're close enough to dial the gate
太好了, 快点吧, 我想赶紧回去!
yes, yes, hurry up and get us back!
把这该死的东西拿掉!
Get this damn thing off me!
我们实在摘不下来
We can't.
那就切掉
Cut it off.
信号一接通赶紧告诉他们有人受伤了
As soon as we establish a connection,
radio back that we've got a medical emergency.
我们或许有什么办法帮她
There must be something we can do for him
去驾驶座旁边把急救箱拿来
There's a emergency first aid kit
behind the pilot seat, get it
少校, 我们试着取下这东西
你只会更疼
Major, everything we do try to remove
just make the pain not worth trying.
现在还不如尽量保持这样
Now try and be still
不能再快点了吗?
Is there no way to go faster?
他正在想办法让我们同时回去
He's just trying to get us back in one piece.
基地控制台, 我是Ford
Atlantis base, this is Ford.
探险者1号准备着陆
我们这里有伤员
Jumper 1 is inbound with
a medical emergency
请回答
Please, respond
怎么了?
What's going on?
探险队说他们有人受伤了
The reconaissance team is reporting
a medical emergency.
我叫了Becket博士,
他正赶过来
I have alerted doctor Becket,
he's on his way.
叫Sheppard少校讲话
Put on major Sheppard.
就是他受伤了
He's the one who's injured.
真希望能找到什么东西把它除掉
How am I expected to find anything
that's gonna get rid of that thing.
能止疼就行!
Something for the pain!
我想外行干不了这个,
我们需要医生!
I don't think that the tylenol is gonna do it,
we need a doctor!
还要多久?
how much longer?
快了
Almost there.
基地, 探险者1号最后校对航道
Flight, Jumper one on final approach.
我是Weir, Sheppard少校的伤势怎么样了?
This is Weir, what's the nature of
Major Sheppard's injury?
几只外星虫子
附着在少校的脖子上了
Some sort of funky alien bug,
attached itself to his neck.
他不能走动了
he's completely immobile
那些虫子做了什么?
What is it doing to him?
我们也不知道
我们那不下来,
We don't know but we can't get it off him,
什么办法都试了就是不行
and we tried everything
把那些东西带回飞船是很危险的
You understand the risk of bringing
something like that, back to Atlantis.
长官我知道. 但是我们没有别的办法
Yes, ma'am I do. But we really
don't have a choice in the matter
好吧, Lieutenant
我知道了
Understood Lieutenant.
祝你好运
Good luck.
对探险者进行隔离检查
Quarantine the jumper bay.
现在开始是自动导航了
It is all automatic from here.
我们到家了
Here we go.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季 第4集
Season 1
Episode 4 : 38 minutes
他们呢?
Where are they?
我也不知道,
I don't know,
通道还敞开着
the gate's still active.
所有指示灯显示他们正在穿过通道
All indications read they should
be through by then.
晕 不是吧!
Oh no!
出什么事了?
What happened?
我们被卡在这了,
The drive pod,
当飞行的时候飞船的两翼是展开的,
我想刚刚没有完全收回
The wing things that stick out when we fly,
must have failed to retract.
我猜是这个原因
That's all I can think it could be.
应该是这个原因, 要不然就是通道关闭了,
我怀疑有这个可能
Of course that, or the Stargate's down,
which I highly doubt.
这回麻烦大了
But this is a big problem
我们怎么办?
What can we do?
我们没什么可做的了,
I don't think there's a thing we can do,
这回真他妈的麻烦大了
this is a-a very, very big problem.
帮个忙
Gimme a hand.
这他妈怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
太奇怪了
That's strange.
是啊
Yes it is.
这是...
That is the...
对, 没错
Yes it is.
有麻烦了
That's creepy sir.
我们被卡在这里了
We're stuck.
没错
Yes, we are.
显然机翼没有及时收回
Apparently the engine pods failed
to retract in time.
一头大一头小,
所以卡在门这了
Square peg, round hole.
我们能把Markham和Stackhouse拉出来吗?
Can we pull Markham and Stackhouse out?
一穿过这门我们的手臂马上消失
Our hands and arms would dematerialize
as soon as we crossed the event horizon.
没办法摸到他们
There's no way to reach for them.
少校
Major
他应该是在受撞击的时候晕过去了
He must have been knocked unconscious
by the impact
探险者1号, 我是Weir
Jumper One, this is Weir
你们那里怎么样了?
What's your status?
我是Ford, 能和你联系上太好了
This is Ford, good to hear your voice
我们有4个人还在这
但是...
The four of us are still here but...
但是Markham和Stackhouse在里面
在通道里面
but Markham and Stackhouse are inside
the event horizon.
再说一遍
Say again
长官, 探险者1号被卡在时空门了
Ma'am, Jumper one is lodged in the stargate.
Teyla, McKay博士, 我还有少校
在飞船后半截
Teyla, doctor McKay and myself
are in the rear compartment with the major.
少校情况不妙
He's in bad shape
Mark和Stockhouse在飞船前半截
Mark and Stockhouse are in the foward section
怎么会这样?
How did that happen?
机器卡住了
Engine pods
我们估计有一个推进器没有完全收回
We think, it was one of the engine pods
但是我们没法子确定
But there's no way to be sure
但那是唯一的可能性
It is the only viable possibility
如果我没听错的话
是不是你们的控制台没有了
If I understand you correctly,
you won't have acces of the flight controls
没错Elizabeth, 推测得很好
Yes Elizabeth, It's an extremely
intriguing conundrum,
而且我还有一件事想说,
and one that I would love
to discuss with you in detail,
当时空门关闭的时候飞船就两半了!
until the stargate shuts down and
the ship is cut in two!
Rodney, 冷静
Rodney!
Rodney, calm down.
我要赶紧想办法抓住你们的飞船
If I'm going to be any help to you at all,
I need to catch up.
让Ford和我说
Lt Ford, back it up for me.
我们在宇宙空间里无法识别幽灵的基地,
We couldn't ID the Wraith base of
operations from space,
就像上次我们到那一样
like we did the last time we were there.
我们着陆在附近为了看的更清楚些
So we went to the same landing co-ordinates
as before, to get a closer look.
没了
It's gone.
什么?
What?
那里应该是座山
This is in the mountain side.
原来是
It was.
我们曾经在那山里
We were inside it.
过去看看
Let's move.
就是以前那个地方
This was the spot.
这个坑比以前那座山还大
That's more a hole than a moutain really.
山被摧毁了?
Could have it been destroyed?
这肯定不是被炸的
This is definitely not a blaster.
嗯 不是
No.
我猜他们走了
I think they picked up and left.
以前是个飞船?
Was a ship?
我不理解, 长官, 整座山都被树覆盖着
I don't know, sir, the mountain was
covered of trees
没错, 但是幽灵冬眠几个世纪, 对吗?
Yeah, but the Wraith's hibernate for centuries, right?
所以有足够时间长出很多树
So a lot of tree's could have
overgrown in that time.
而我们被囚禁在其中一个大飞船里
就是我在图上给你指出来的那个
Then we were held prisoner inside one of
the great ships I showed you in the drawings.
他们走了, 开始屠戮整个世界
They've left, to begin culling worlds.
那边有动静
There's movement down there.
快跑!
Go!
她不会明白的
She hardly mean't, begin at the beginning.
这些事她应该知道
This is intel, she needs to know
我们现在还有不到38分钟
And we have less than 38 minutes
等会儿, 为什么只有38分钟?
Hold on, why 38 minutes?
因为在非活动状态下
时空门最多保持38分钟开启状态
Because that's the maximum amount of time a Stargate
remain open in non-relativistic conditions
这是热力物理学定义之一,
It is one of the more immutable laws
of the worm holes physics,
而且天啊, 看看表,
最多还有35分钟. 你吸住我们的飞船了吗?
and oh my, look at the time,
it's more like 35 minutes. Are we all caught up?
我知道了
I get it
你需要什么?
What do you need?
帮忙
Help
好啦!
All right!
叫Cavenaugh, Groden和Simpson来这里
看看他们有什么主意
Let me put Cavenaugh, Groden and Simpson in a room.
See what they come up with.
很好, Czech, Czech,
别忘了叫Czech
That's good, and the Czech, Czech,
the Czech with name i cant remember
Zelenka博士?
Doctor Zelenka?
就是他们. 这是我们一起研究的
That's it. We'll work it at our end.
还有谁?
What else?
我们再联系, 谢了
We call you, thank you
病人在哪?
Where is my patient?
-有点麻烦. 去会议室
-哦, 不是吧...
-There's been a problem. Conference room.
-Oh, no...
保持和他们联系
Keep a channel open with them all the times
把报警器关了!
And turn that alarm off!
Hi Teyla!
你没事吧?
Are you allright?
我没事
I am fine
看起来我们还没回基地
Something tells me, we haven't
made it to Atlantis yet.
没有
No
Ford?
那是什么玩意儿?
What is that?
长官, 我们卡住了
We stucks, Sir
我们在哪?
We're what?
在时空门中间
In a gate
也就是说我们快玩儿完了
You mean my day just got worse.
据我们推测
应该有1,2个推进器没有收回
We're going with the assumption,
that it was one or both of the drive pods.
我不知道是不是机器出了故障
I don't know if it was mechanical failure.
要不就是当咱们起飞的时候机器被击中了
Or was damaged as we try to take off.
不要停
Taking fire.
要不我们就完蛋了!
It's a melt to do!
我在劲力!
I try Sir!
没有办法证实
Is no way of knowing, really
但是如果有懂一些机械常识 ...
But, if you know some way of mannually
crack the mechanism ...
Cokpit跟过来了
Cokpit on their left
cokpit在那个时候分子化了,
但是...
the cokpit is regretably demolecularize,
at the moment, but...
你发现什么了吗?
Loose someone back here?
- 没有
- 应该没有
- No
- No, I dont think so
如果你不介意, 我在这里读点东西
Well if you'll excuse me, I'll be a foot and a half
over there, taking some readings.
你们慢慢聊吧
Feel free to talk amongst yourselves.
你们了解大致情况了吧
我们还有不到半个小时
Alright, you've all been briefed.
We have less than half an hour.
Zelenka博士呢?
Where this doctor Zelenka?
他在做2号小型模拟飞机
He's working up a simulation
in the Puddle-Jumper Two
- 那个模拟机可以直接到找到他们
- 太好了
- It was direct toward there
- That is good
前提是要有足够的时间
If there was time it would be
博士, 现在不是讨论它的功能的时候
It is not a matter that features yet, doctor.
飞船上有6个人
There's 6 people on a ship
我只是个医疗博士,
所以请原谅我问一个愚蠢的问题
I'm just a medical doctor here,
so forgive me if this is a stupid question
如果他们走进时空门
If they just step to the event horizon
当门关闭的时候,
他们不能回到飞船控制台吗?
wouldn't they come through to the front
part of the ship, when the gate shuts down?
飞船前面一段不能被重组
The front half won't rematerialise on this side.
时空门只能传送完整物体
The Stargate transmits the matter in discreet units
飞船前面一段不能被重组,
The front half of the ship cannot rematerialise,
除非整个飞船都通过时空门
Until the whole ship has crossed
into the event horizon
时空门只能接受没有中断的介质
The Stargate is a century waiting for
the contiguous components
也就是说飞船和里面所有的东西
Meaning the jumper and everyone inside
在我们传送他们之前,
必须都通过了时空门
To enter completely,
before we can transport them
他的意思是说时空门只能传送一阵个物体
He say's, the gate only sends
things through in one piece.
我听明白了
Yeah, sorry
很不幸, 直到分子重组完成之前
Unfortunately, the upgoing Stargate
won't transmit the matter stream
上传的时空门是不会传送任何流状介质的
until the demolecularization is completed
当门关闭的时候
When he shuts down
整个飞船前身, 还有里面所有的人都会消失
entire forward section, along with
the men inside will cease to exist
其他人呢?
And what about the others?
飞船会在瞬间沿着时空门被切割
The ship will be severed instantaneously
along the event horizon
他们将被抛向真空宇宙,
They'll be exposed to hard vacuum,
现在还有29分钟
In 29 minutes
他们如果关闭后舱门呢?
What if they close the bulkhead door?
整个飞船后部会是密闭的,
起到了一个救生艇的作用
The rear portion of the ship,
will remain pressurised. Become a sort of lifeboat.
他们很快就没有氧气了
It will lose atmosphere very quickly
那么我们就有时间派另一个飞船去接他们了
It could buy enough time to send
a second Jumper.
那又怎么样?
And do what?
有办法了!
Figure it out!
和探险者1号取得联系
告诉他们这个建议
Contact Jumper One and made recommendation
你干什么?
What are you doing?
对不起
Sorry, here
探险者1号, 我是基地
Jumper One, this is Atlantis
我听到了
We're still here.
我们建议你们关闭后舱门
We recommend closing the bulkhead door.
哦... 好主意
Oh... Good thinking
然后呢?
What else?
我们还在想办法
再和你联系
We are still working on the problem.
We'll get back to you.
完毕
Atlantis base out.
谢谢你和我们联系!
Thanks for calling!
除了我还有人怕黑吗?
Somebody else is claustrophobic
or is it just me?
为什么关闭舱门?
Why did you close the doors?
当时空门关闭,
飞船前部被割断的时候,
So that when the Stargate is close down,
and the forward section is severed,
我们就不会被抛向外太空了
we're not directly exposed to space
这门结实吗?
Will it hold?
用潜水艇材质做的,
我想可以...
Like a screen door in a submarine,
I just prefer apoxia...
...起到减压的作用
...to decompression.
这... 这只是个人想法
It is... it is a personal thing
快没空气了
我看你还是冷静点吧
The air's gonna get thin in here.
Your really do have to calm down.
- 哦, 如果不这么做27分钟以后你就知道什么是缺氧了
- McKay
- Oh, you wait and see how thin it get's in 27 minutes.
真空的宇宙. 那才叫缺氧
Vacuum. That's thin.
把门打开
Knock it off
哦, 我觉得只有我认识到了我们现在处境多危险!
Oh, I apologise for being the only person
who truly comprehends how screwed we are!
别和我谈危险!
Don't talk to me about screwed!
我们不应该放弃Markham和Stackhouse
And let's not give up on
Markham and Stackhouse, either.
我们还有很多时间想办法,
There's plenty of time to solve this thing,
首先你最好闭上嘴,
好好动动脑子
but you've gotta stop using your mouth,
and start using your brain.
对不起...我只是...
I'm sorry...I'm just...
这是人到生死关头的正常反映
我知道这样不对..
I react to certain doom, in a certain way.
It's a bad habit and..
也许有办法手动让推进器收回
Maybe there is a way to manually
retract the mechanism.
我想应该可以
Yeah maybe there is.
给你这个
Here
你很坚强
You seem stronger
不. 只是现在不那么疼了
No.it's just the pains not so bad now.
很好
That's good
不, 我不觉得
No, It isn't
因为我的腿没知觉了
I can't feel my legs
手和胳膊都是麻的
The hands and the arms are numb
我基本不能动了
I can barely move them.
我快失去知觉了. 少尉
feelings creeping me out. Look lieutenant
我只想告诉你
What I'm trying to say
如果我不能把这东西取下去
is if you don't get this damn thing off me.
我会比你先死
I have even less time than you do.
Zelenka博士
Doctor Zelenka
对不起我没有参加会议,
Weir博士, 我实在没有时间
Apologise to not attending a breefing,
Dr Weir, there was not time.
我不想妨碍你
但是我想知道你在做什么
I don't want to slow you down but
I need to know what you're working on
这样我可以告诉探险者1号
so I can communicate it to the team
on Jumper one.
我们正在努力 ...
We are attempting to retract the ...
把推进器收回到飞船后舱
the drive pod back into the fuse lodge
from inside the rear compartment
有什么进展了吗?
Anything yet?
远古科技很复杂
There is much redundancy
in the ancient technology.
所以我先在这里做个试验
Making it dangerous for them
to experiment with it in this way.
也就是说飞船后门有可能打开
他们就被抛向外太空
So they might accidentally open the rear
hatch or shut life support off entirely.
是的, 是的, 没错
Yes, yes, yes
这就是为什么我要先做个试验
It's just why we're attempting to isolate
the correct control pathway.
明白了. 我有什么能帮上忙的?
Understood. What can I do to help?
别和我聊天就行了
Stop talking, please.
少尉,
Lieutenant,
拿刀把这东西切开
get your knife out and cut this damn thing off.
这回他不能在怎么伤到我了
It can't hurt as much as it did last time.
上次你差点死了
The last time, we almost lost you
算了, 我怎么样都会死的
Ah well.you're going to lose me anyway
长官
Sir
我们回到飞船上的时候已经试过切掉它了
We tried to cut it off when
we were back on the planet
各种方法都试了
We tried everything
长官你能坚持吧?
You're right sir?
准备好了
Here we go.
任何办法只会让能更难受
Everything we did just seemed to hurt you more.
我想它可以自我治疗
I think it just heals itself.
它吸收你的能量, 就像那些幽灵
it feeds on your strengh, like the Wraith
你和我说过了
You had to say that.
我父亲给我讲过许多关于这种生物的故事
My father often told stories about
creatures such like this.
我一直以为他想让我们这些孩子呆在营地
I always thought he was just trying to keep
the children from straying far from our camp.
很好, 他告诉过你怎么杀了他们吗?
Great, and did he
tell you how to kill it?
我不知道,
我确信我们杀不了它
I don't know sir,
I'm sure we can't.
我想到了另一个办法
I could use a second opinion
和基地取得联系
Get back on the radio
收到
Affirmative
过来吧长官, 接通了
Come here Sir, this micro is open.
我是Beckett医生, 伤员怎么样?
This is doctor Beckett, how is our patient?
我是Ford. Sheppard少校苏醒了
但是那个生物还在他身上
This if ford. Major Sheppard is conscious
but the creature is still latched on to him.
大夫能不能来就诊啊?
How do you feel about house calls doc?
我也想
但是你实在太远了
Would if I could major Sheppard but
you'll have to settle for long distance.
我听说有东西附在你身上了
I'm told you have something of a cling-on
很可笑吧
It's funny
是你见过最丑陋的东西了
It's like the ugliest damn thing you've ever seen.
它怎么攻击到你的?
How did it attack yourself ?
我们在回飞船的路上
Well, we returned toward the Jumper
幽灵们向我们开枪
The Wraith were shooting us
我掩护你
你去告诉Marco准备起飞
Go tell Marco to get ready for
take off I'll cover you.
你怎么办?
What about you?
我这就回去, 快走!
I'll be there in a minute, GO!
少校回飞船的路被截住了
Major we're cut off from the jumper
不行
Negative
有一个在你3点钟位置
另外两个被我引过来了
They're should be one at your three o'clock
I drew the other two this way
我们被包围了
他们从哪出来的?
They're all around us where'd they come from?
少尉你应该知道他们能够隐身的,
Ltd you know how they can make you
see things that aren't there,
你前面现在没有人, 赶紧跑!
The path in front of you is cleared, now move!
你能描述一下吗?
Can you describe it to me?
好的
Yes sir.
包括尾巴它一共2英尺长,
还有点什么东西在他胳膊下面
It's about two feet in length including the tail,
there's rough stuff under his arm picks
有两个带刺的东西在少校脖子上
靠近颈动脉
It's got two sharp spiny things in his neck
near the Major's carotid artery
描述的再细致点
I need more than that, son
4条像腿的东西
Four legs, if you can call them that
紧紧的包住了少校的喉咙
They're wrapped around the Major's throat.
找不到眼睛
I can't see any eyes
有很坚硬的外壳, 但是肚子下面很松软
It's got a real hard shell, but there's
a soft meaty part underneath.
少校, 你有什么感觉?
Major, what are your physical symptoms?
就好像用刀刺我的眼
Well, first it was as a knife in the eye
因为我现在没有什么知觉了
Since I have lost all the feelings
in my extremities
我不能动
I can't move
这么说初期感到疼痛
So it incapacitates first with pain and prophases.
我想去帮McKay检查机器故障
I need to be able to move around
and help McKay with mechanical problem.
如果不想办法
Marco和Stackhouse会死的
Marco and Stackhouse are dead if I don't.
你们都试过什么办法了?
What have you tryed?
试过用刀切, 用火烧,
我甚至用枪打它
I've tried to cut it off, I've tried to burn it off,
I've even tried to shoot it off.
很近的点射
9 mil point blank.
除了差点杀了少校以外,
没有任何效果
Not much worse I can do without
killing the Major along with it.
我相信这个生物属于那些幽灵
I believe the creature is related
in some way to the Wraith
真的?
really ?
为什么这么说?
How so?
它不断吸Sheppard少校的血来维持生命
it feeds itself after each intent to remove him
by sucking life from Major Sheppard
和那些幽灵一样
Just as the Wraith would.
我估计是幽灵放出了什么东西
Well, I suppose the Wraith has
to have evolved of something
我估计是一种...
史前的某种东西
I suppose that it is a sort of a...
prehistoric cousin.
大夫听着, 少校不能这样下去
Listen Doctor, the Major can't be worse
我们要想点办法
We gonna do something right now
你刚刚说这个生物的腹部很软而且他还吸血
You said that the creature had a underside
an exposed  soft tissue like a leech
我试过把它割开
I tried to cut into it.
那东西差点杀死少校
the thing practically strangled him to death
你不要切掉它
在它身上洒点盐
Son you don't cut leeches off.
You pour salt on to them.
如果你启动磁场他们都会死
If you activate the field they'll die.
如果他们解决了这个问题
我们可以一起打开磁场
We can always open it together
if they fix the problem
他们没有时间了
Well they may not have time.
如果不这么做他们会毁掉这个设备
If they don't, we could destroy this facility.
我是想让你们想个解决方法
It's supposed we're working on solutions.
我们估计飞船一开始就损坏了
We think the Jumper must be damaged
for this to have happened in the first place.
把远古系统提速是个驾驶错误
Ancient systems are too advanced
for this to be pilot error.
那么怎么样?
So ?
那么就取决于损坏程度有多大
So depending on the extend of the damage
我们不能保证因此而产生的能量不反馈到别的地方
we can't rule out a catastrophic power
feed back in the drive manifolds.
请不要用术语
Without the techno babble please.
Cavenaugh博士, 只是想说,
有一点可能性,
Doctor Cavenaugh, was pointing out,
that there's a very slim chance,
飞船没有控制台,
推进器又受损,
that with the cockpit controls interrupted,
and with the pod damaged,
飞船有可能超载
the main drive could overload.
她的意思是爆炸
She means to say explode.
特别是当McKay开始检查线路,
Especially if McKay starts nosing around
inside the control conduits,
尝试整修推进器的时候
to attract the drive pod manually.
他肯定会的. 我知道我会这么做
And he will. I know I would.
Zelenka正在想办法
我刚刚从那里回来
Zelenka's working on simulations.
I just came from there.
如果超负荷
If there is a catastrophic overload.
爆炸会毁掉整个飞船,
The full force of the explosion
will break up the Jumper,
碎片会顺着时空门飞进来
就像个炸弹
follow the burning fragments through
the Stargate, like a bomb.
你们认为这种危险性很小么?
You think the risk of
this happening is minimal?
我觉得很小
In my opinion. Yes.
你们都同意?
You all agree?
那么就试试吧
Then we take the chance.
我认为说清楚这种危险性很重要
I thought it was important
to point out the risk.
没错, 你说清楚了
Fine, you did.
现在请多想想他们的生命,
不要总想着你自己....
Now please worry a little bit more about
their  lives, and less about your own ass....
还有23分钟
23 minutes.
Weir博士?
Doctor Weir?
对不起, 我现在没有时间
I'm sorry, I don't have time right now.
这些人不是想拿回这艘飞船
Neither do those people that are trapped
aboard the ship of the ancestors.
消息传得真快
News travels fast.
当你们探险队员呼救的时候
我和她谈了
I was speaking with one of your expedition
members, when she was called in to help.
好吧, 我应该知道我们没有时间了
Well then, you are aware that
we are very short on time.
我知道
I am.
但还是很重要
Still, this is important.
好吧
Ok
你不知道一件事
但是在我们中间,
You do not know this.
But among our people,
有一个仪式祷告者刚刚说
死亡临近他们了
there is a ritual prayer that is said,
when one knows that death is upon them.
我们不这么认为
We don't know that it is.
有人告诉我这是不可避免的
I'm told that it is all but inevitable.
谁说的?
By who?
那不重要
It is not important.
重要的是, Teyla已经准备好死了
What is important, is that Teyla
be allowed to prepare for death.
要知道一个人死亡的时间和地点,
对于我们来说是很珍贵的
Knowing the time and place of one's end,
is a very rare thing among our people.
只是个简单的仪式, 只需要一点时间....
It is a simple rite, but will not take more
than a few moments to....
Hollan? 我们要劲我们全力来就他们
Hollan? We need to concentrate all of
our efforts on saving them.
此时此刻Teyla自己的信念是什么?
At the risk of forsaking Teyla's own beliefs?
重要的是我们要用我们现有很少的时间
尽我们最大的努力....
It is important that we use what
little time we have, to try everything....
这件事上,
不用你告诉我什么重要什么不重要
I would ask you not to tell me what is important,
and what is not, in this case.
- 对不起, 现在我没有时间聊天
- 为什么不行?
- I'm sorry, I can't have this conversation right now.
- Why not?
因为我们在浪费时间
Because we are wasting time.
这一时刻Teyla早就准备好了
This is time that Teyla can use to prepare.
好了, 你认为死亡是必然的
Alright, you perceive death
a certain way.
我也承认. I事实上, 我也尊重你们的想法
I accept that. In fact, I respect that.
但是我们没有准备去死
我们必须尽力去避免死亡
But we do not prepare for death.
We do everything we can to stave it off.
这才是我们应该做的
That is who we are.
我并不想中止你的工作
I'm not asking you to suspend your efforts.
你想让我告诉这飞船上所有人,
No. You want me to tell
everyone on that ship,
他们最好还是安心等死?
that they should expect to die?
我不会说的
I will not send them that message.
并且如果你觉得这样侵犯了Teyla的权利,
我向你道歉
And if you feel that, that violates
Teyla's rights, I apologise.
我会道歉的. 但是现在不是时候
我必须走了
I truly do. But there's nothing I can do
about that right now. I have to go.
很好. 现在我们手头上
有了所有探险者1号人员名单
Alright. We've got everything to
the Jumper manifest, already laid out here.
你那里有什么可以利用的工具
What's your personal inventory.
我这有把瑞士军刀
Alright, from the vest,
we got a swiss army knife.
一些巧克力, 还有点水
火柴, 急救包
Some chocolate, some water.
Matches, emergency kit.
还有些酒精, 碘酒, 止疼片
We have alcohol, iodine, pain killers
这是什么?
What is this?
Teyla在飞船储藏室找到一个心脏起搏器
Teyla found a portable difibrillator
in the ships storage.
我在想. 如果Sheppard少校被电击,
那生物有可能杀了他
I thought of that. If Major Sheppard received
the same electric shock, it would likely kill him.
没错
Right
什么都试试. 每次试一样
Try everything. One item at a time.
Weir博士!
Dr Weir!
Cavenaugh, 你是不是有什么新发现
Cavenaugh, I hope you've got
something to tell me.
是的
Yes, I do.
他妈的怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
你说什么?
Excuse me?
我很高兴离开SGC, 因为我,
因为我可以参军了,
I happily left the SGC, because I had,
had it up to here, with the military running things,
你却不让我参与秘密研究
and you just busted me like a private.
别总胡思乱想, 这没什么秘密
Don't be so dramatic, besides
the Air Force doesn't have privates.
不止是我. 你撤掉了我整个研究小组的职务
Neither do I. You just cut them off.
Right in front of my research team.
就为了这事? 你有什么不满吗?
That's what this is about? You're embarrassed?
我承认确实有点丢人
Well humiliated would be a little more accurate.
我顾及不到任何人的颜面
I haven't worked up to humiliation yet.
我只是做了个假设,
只是做了一个普通市民应该做的
I just assumed, that with a civilian in charge of
the expedition, there would be a little bit more.
我们已经不再是一个市民,
我们和地球隔绝了
A civilian is in charge,
and we are cut off from Earth.
整个基地就好像一个大移民
Which makes Atlantis,
almost like a colony.
我明白这点
I suppose.
那好,
我是这里的主管
Well I'm governor of that colony.
说得真好
Well that's all very well and good.
你有什么异议吗?
Do you have a problem with that?
你没明白我的意思
You're missing my point.
不是, 是你没明白我的意思
No, you're missing mine.
如果你再因为你的自私
If you waste one more minute,
which could be used
浪费救出他们的宝贵的每1分钟,
to help the people trapped
on that ship, because of your ego?
我保证我会把你送到一个孤星上,
I promise you, I will dial the co-ordinates
of a very lonely planet,
在那里你永远是最主要的
where you can be as self important
as you wanna be.
你认为我在开玩笑?
You think I'm kidding?
你不会这么做的
You wouldn't do that.
Cavenaugh? 回去工作
Cavenaugh? Get back in there.
这件事我们以后再谈
We'll talk about this later.
没有下一次了. 滚!
Never again. Go!
滚!
Go!
Zalinka博士, 请接控制室
Dr Zalinka to control room.
我有新发现了
I think I have something
我们在接受信号
We're receiving.
探险者1号, 我是Weir
Jumper One, this is Weir.
Zelenka博士有新发现
Doctor Zelenka's come up with something.
Zelenka. 为什么我总忘不掉你?
Zelenka. Why can I never
remember that name?
他已经找到了
飞船推进器的主控系统
He's positively identified the control systems in the
port side of the Jumper, that retract the drive pod.
我正在用同样方法控制你的系统
I'm relaying the schematics to your data pad.
太好了, 我们有救了
Thank you, now we're getting somewhere.
什么?
What?
Zelenka找出了推进器的控制系统
Zelenka's identified the control pathways
to the engine pod,
也就是说现在修好机器的比率从万分之一
上升到了千分之一
which means that's increasing my chances of fixing this,
from one in a million, to one in a thousand.
但是, 有件事. Elizabeth
But, it's something. Elizabeth.
什么事?
Yes?
如果机器超负荷我只有7-9秒通知你,
I'll only have 7 to 9 seconds to warn you if I
accidentally do a catastrophic overload,
所以我让你开启防御系统的时候
你不要犹豫
so if I tell you to raise the shields.
Don't hesitate.
我们知道危险性
你尽力吧
We're aware of the risk Rodney.
Do your best.
先试试碘酒
Starting with iodine.
碘酒被吸收了
Scratch iodine.
你那还有什么?
What else have you got there?
对啊, 你还有什么? 有什么吃的吗?
Yes, what have you got there? Any food?
你开玩笑
You're kidding.
我只有不到20分钟来救咱们 ,
而我现在都快低血糖了, 所以....
I have less than 20 minutes to save our lives,
and I am teetering on the brink of a
hypoglycemic reaction, so....
谢谢
Thank you
我现在试酒精
I'm gonna try alcohol now.
放一点到它的肚皮上,
看看有神么反映
Place a few drops on the soft tissue,
to see how it reacts.
给我留点
Save some for me.
这酒精不能喝
Wrong type of alcohol sir.
这种有什么好处?
What's the good of that?
没什么
Not much sir.
还是没有反映
No reaction to alcohol.
好吧, 下一个是什么?
Right, What next?
医生没说洒点盐在这生物上吗?
Did the Doctor not say to pour salt
on the creature?
我想这不用说. 你就试试所有的东西吧
I think that was a metaphor. But it doesn't matter.
Just try everything.
水. 给我点水
Water. Give me water.
长官.长官.你没事吧. 长官? 少校?
Sir.Sir.Sir are you alright. Sir? Major?
你没事吧. 长官? 少校?
Sir are you alright? Sir? Major?
少校怎么了?
Major What's happening?
到底怎么了
What's happening
那东西对水或者是盐产生了反映
It reacted to either the salt or the water.
或者是两个一起的反映
Or a combination of both.
它掉下来了吗?
Did it lose it's hold on Major Sheppard?
没有
Negative
它抓得更紧了
If anything, it dug in more.
别试了
Please don't do that again.
我不会了, 对不起长官
I won't sir, sorry.
好像它对盐水有种抵抗
Looks like they have a primitive
defence to salt water.
它动了
当你把他推向电路板的时候,
It moved.
When you threw him across the circuits,
我感到引擎启动了一下,
但是很快又停了
I think the engine fired for a microsecond,
but it stopped.
哦 不是吧
Oh no.
怎么了?
What?
可以实行A计划了
So much for plan A.
怎么了?
What?
当时空门关闭的时候
When the Stargate closes now,
这里所有的分子的运动,
都会导致这里的冲击
every molecule of air in this compartment,
is gonna out rush out through there.
我们向前滑动了一点
We slid in further.
还有15分钟
15 minutes.
Ford, 你那里怎么样了?
Ford, what can you tell me?
我们的飞船移动了一点
The Puddle Jumper has shifted slightly.
现在飞船后端暴露在时空门前面了
The rear compartment has now
breached the event horizon.
McKay博士
Dr McKay.
McKay博士, 还是希望我们能及时收回推进器
Dr McKay, is still hopeful we can retract
the drive pod in time.
明白了
Understood.
我们现在没有任何新进展
但是时间不多了
We haven't come up with anything yet.
But there's still time.
明白
Yes ma'am.
Sheppard少校怎么样了?
How is Major Sheppard?
我还活着
I'm still here.
坚持住
我们还在研究
Hang in there Major.
We're working on the problem.
我知道你们在努力
I know you are.
听着, 我想在我还能说话的时候说几句想说的
Listen, I'd like to say something,
while I still can.
不要! 你会没事的
Don't! You're gonna get through this.
他不会让我死的
If I was. He wouldn't have let me go.
谁不会让你死?
Who wouldn't have let you go?
幽灵们
The Wraith.
我才他没有杀我,
是因为在他眼里我这样比死了更好
I guess he saw me as good as dead,
cos he just walked away.
所以, 我想说的是....
So, what I wanted to say was....
留着力气等回来和我说
Save your strength John.
And tell me in person.
这很重要
This is important.
我在听
I'm listening.
我们能把他送回基地
We should sent him through the event horizon.
如果McKay博士及时解决了问题,
我们就让少校赶紧回去
If Doctor McKay figures it out in time,
we can fix the Major up on the other side.
如果他不行了, 我们也都死
If he doesn't, we're all dead anyway.
不要给我压力
No pressure.
Sheppard少校不要那么急躁
Major Sheppard would effectively be in suspended
animation for the entire time.
- 我们不能冒这个险
- 为什么不行?
- We can't risk that.
- Why not?
如果这个生物对水有反映,
If the creature reacted that violently
to drops of water,
谁也不知道它对时空门有没有什么反映
who knows how it would react
to Stargate travel.
你的意思是说,
只要教授身上有这东西他就不能过时空门?
Are you telling me Major Sheppard can't come
through the gate, while that thing is on him?
那么我们现在必须抓紧了!
Then we must do something now!
用起搏器杀了我
Hit me with the defibrillator.
少校你一定是想到什么了
You may be onto something Major.
你说过他可能会死的
You said that might kill him.
我们就是这么想的
That's the idea.
我不明白
I don't understand.
Teyla. 你说过这生物和幽灵差不多
Teyla. You said this creature was like a Wraith.
是的
Yes.
那么你试想一下
如果上帝让少校死, 他们会怎么做,
Then how do you think it would respond,
if God forbit,
Sheppard少校那上死掉, 那么...
Major Sheppard were to die right now, then.
它就不再附着少校了
It would stop feeding.
没错. 幽灵就会这样
Exactly. Just as a Wraith would.
你们到底是怎么想的?
How is that an idea?
我们只是想欺骗这个生物
它的寄生体已经死了
I'm suggesting that we fool the creature into
thinking that its prey's dead,
所以我们必须让少校停止心跳
by stopping the Major's heart.
如果想法没错. 它会离开少校的
If I'm right. It should let him go.
一旦生物离开
我们就再击一次让少校苏醒
If that thing let's go.
We give him another jolt.
试一下. 如果不行,
就把他扔进时空门
Give it a try. If it doesn't work,
send him through the event horizon.
他会暂时呆在那
He'll keep there,
as good as the deep freeze.
John, 你确定你要这么做么?
John, are you sure you wanna do this?
我真的很想把这该死的东西除掉
I want this damn thing off me.
准备对探险者1号进行急救
Be prepared for a code blue in the Jumper bay.
Ford少尉, 你知道怎么做吧?
Lt Ford, do you know how to do this?
- 是的. 把他衣服割开
- 什么?
- Yes sir. Cut his shirt off.
- What?
把他衣服割开!
Cut his shirt off!
200幅. 把他的饰物那开
Charging 200. Move his tags.
- 什么?
- 那开里面的胸牌
- What?
- Move his chain, inside.
在表面擦点油
Place the lubrication,right on the paddles.
准备好了
Ready to go.
一旦这虫子掉下来我一定杀了它
Once the bug falls off, I'm gonna have to kill it.
准备下一次,
然后我们再帮你苏醒
Ready to charge up again,
and we'll hit it with another jolt.
McKay, 如果我们第一下不成功,
我们必须再次打开那舱门.
McKay, if we can't restart his heart on the first try,
we'll need that bulkhead door open again.
好的
Done.
我们其中一个必须带他过去
One of us is gonna have to get him through.
我来
I will.
开始吧!
Do it!
没有心跳!
No pulse!
下不来
It won't come off.
冷静. 也许需要一段时间
Settle. It may take a moment.
少尉?
Lieutenant?
没反映?
Nothing?
没反映! 快带他过去
Nothing! Let's get him through.
- 好了?
- 是的
- Got him?
- Yes.
我是Ford少尉. 那个生物已经取下来了
This is Lt Ford. The creature has been
sucessfully removed from Major Sheppard,
但是我们无法让他苏醒. 他和Teyla,
现在在时空门的另一端
but we were unable to revive him. Both he and Teyla,
are now on the other side of the event horizon.
谢谢你Rodney少尉, 你们还有7分钟
Thank you Lt. Rodney, you have seven minutes.
我只解决了一部分,
但是我们快没时间了. 我们可能做不到了
I'm only halfway through the possible circuit pathways,
and times almost up. We're not gonna make it.
你就做吧. 现在还有时间
Just keep on it. There's still time.
你应该进时空门里面
You should consider stepping
into the event horizon.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我会坚持到最后的, 但是给你个选择,
最好还是离开
I'll keep trying till the end, but given your choices,
that's a far better way to go.
把你一个人留在这个危险的地方?
Leave you here alone with that thing
wrapped up in my jacket?
你确定那东西死了
- 肯定死了
You did check to make sure it was dead.
- It's dead.
很好, 因为爆炸性减压, 然后窒息死亡, 是很有可能....
Good, because explosive decompression, and death
by suffocation with that thing, is possibly....
- 干你的活!
- 对不起
- Work!
- I'm sorry
还有多久?
Time?
2分20秒
2 minutes 20 seconds.
Rodney, 又过了2分钟
Rodney, we're down to 2 minutes
我知道时间. 我现在还有2打线路没有试
I know the time. I've still got over two dozen
circuits I haven't tried.
不用按照顺序来. 随意试哪一个
Don't be so methodical. Just pick one at random.
如果那么做, 那样的话我就同时运行了2个系统
If I do that, I run the risk of attempting to
activate the same circuit twice.
试试吧!
Just try!
我告诉你, 那根本不可能....
I'm telling you, there's no way I could....
等等
Wait.
我想我成功了
I think I did it.
Elizabeth?
我估计推进器收回了
I think the engine pods retracted.
为什么还是看不到你们?
Why haven't you shown up?
对啊. 为什么我们还是不动?
She's right. Why aren't we moving?
是惯性. 飞船是靠惯性穿过时空门的
It's inertia. The drive shift end went
through the Stargate.
我们有没有任何前进的动力了
We've shed all our forward momentum.
你再浪费时间. 任何一个力,
都会给予一个相同的反力
You're wasting your time. For every action,
there is an equal and opposite reaction.
那么我们该怎么办?
Then what are we gonna do?
还有一分钟
One minute.
后舱. 让后舱爆炸
The rear hatch. Blow the rear hatch.
那么就有足够的力让怎么穿过去了
It should give you enough thrust
to make it through.
可以这么做. 但是只有一个机器可以引爆
I can do it. But the only mechanism
to blow the hatch is back here.
我来. 没时间了. 快走!
I'll do it. There's no time. Just go!
30秒
30 seconds.
我去通道
I'll be in the Jumper bay.
再来一次!
Again!
他会没事的
He's gonna be fine.
干得不错Rodney
Well done Rodney.
看着吧
We'll see.
有脉搏了
We've got a pulse.
心跳越来越强了
It's getting stronger.
他很快就没事了
He's going to be ok.
感觉如何?
How are you feeling?
饿
Starving.
他可弄了不少吻痕, 但是Beckett医生说
他几天就好
He's got quite the hickey, but Dr Beckett says
he'll be fine in a few days.
你需要休息
We should let you rest.
不, 你应该给我点吃的
No, you should get me food.
我想可以安排
I think we can arrange that.
早日康复
Welcome back sir.
这真是个奇迹
I must admit, it is a pleasant surprise.
顺便说一下. 你上次想说什么?
By the way. What were you gonna say?
什么时候?
When?
在你认为... 你知道的
Before, when you thought... ou know
哦 那件事啊
Oh that.
那时候我没让你说
但是现在我想知道
I didn't want you to say at the time.
But now I'm curious.
我那时候想说...
I was gonna say...
你们大家要互相照顾
Take care of each other.
不错
That's nice.
我们也是这么做的
And indeed we did.
是的你做到了. 再次感谢
Yes you did. Thank you, again.
没什么
You're welcome.
晚安
Goodnight.
你一定不是想说那句话,
对吧?
You weren't really gonna say that,
were you?
我不知道你想说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
你一定知道
I didn't think so.